Aha, mm.
啊哈，嗯。
These pancakes
are delicious, Sandy.
这些煎饼
很好吃，桑迪。
But what do you call
this sweet stuff?
但你叫什么
这个甜的东西？
That's maple syrup.
那是枫糖浆。
It's kinda like jelly
that comes from trees.
有点像果冻
来自树木。
Tree jelly?
树果冻？
Gross.
I prefer mine on tap.
总的。
我更喜欢我的现成的。
Oww!
哇！
Welcome to Bikini Bottom's
欢迎来到比基尼泳裤
very first
Arbor Day celebration!
第一次
植树节庆祝活动！
Barber Day?
理发日？
Well, I could use a trim.
嗯，我可以使用修剪。
I think she said Harbor Day,
我想她说的是港口日，
to celebrate old Navy swabs
like meself!
庆祝老海军拭子
就像我自己一样！
It's Ar-bor Day!
今天是植树节！
It's a day to celebrate
the joy of trees.
这是一个值得庆祝的日子
树木的欢乐。
But, Sandy, you've got
the only tree in town.
但是，桑迪，你有
镇上唯一的树。
Correction,
I used to have the only tree,
更正，
我曾经拥有唯一的一棵树，
'cause today you're all gonna
grow your own tree.
因为今天你们都会
种植你自己的树。
- Ah.
- Ooh.
- 啊。
- 哦。
Trees don't grow underwater.
树木不会在水下生长。
Oh, these little
fellers will.
哦，这些小
伙计们会的。
I've used the power of science
我运用了科学的力量
to make special acorns
that will grow
制作特殊的橡子
会成长的
into saltwater trees,
进入咸水树，
Oh, aww.
Hello, little tree.
哦，哇。
你好，小树。
There you go.
Ooh, look at that.
就这样吧。
哦，看看那个。
Oh.
哦。
Huh? Oh.
啊？哦。
Mmm.
嗯。
You don't need to chew it,
you whittle stick!
不需要咀嚼，
你这个削木棍！
To keep your tree healthy,
all you need to do
为了保持你的树健康，
你需要做的一切
is give it lots of fertilizer.
就是给它大量的肥料。
Not a problem.
不是问题。
One more thing,
还有一件事，
to grow a happy,
well-rounded tree,
成长为幸福的人，
树形圆润，
you need to talk to 'em.
你需要和他们谈谈。
- Hi, I'm SpongeBob.
- Hey, little feller.
- 嗨，我是海绵宝宝。
- 嘿，小家伙。
- Testing, testing.
- Hello.
- 测试，测试。
- 你好。
I love talking to someone
who knows how to keep a secret.
我喜欢和某人说话
谁知道如何保守秘密。
I can finally tell someone
what really happened
我终于可以告诉别人
到底发生了什么
when I pulled that job
in Shell City.
当我撤掉那份工作时
在贝壳城。
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
Don't worry little fella.
别担心小家伙。
You'll have lots
of people talking to you.
你会有很多
与你交谈的人。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
I would like to speak
to the proprietor.
我想发言
给业主。
The complaint department's
over there.
投诉部门的
在那儿。
Talk to the tree.
和树说话。
Mr. Tree,
the condiment distribution
树先生，
调味品分配
of my patty is subpar.
我的肉饼很差劲。
Hm, if talking
to a tree is good for it,
嗯，如果说话的话
对一棵树来说是有好处的，
I'll bet a little smooth jazz
must be amazing.
我打赌会是一点流畅的爵士乐
一定很神奇。
Ho-ho!
嗬嗬！
I'll talk to you
the way nature intended,
我会和你谈谈
自然的方式，
with television!
有电视！
We now return to
"My Mother the Barnacle.
我们现在回到
“我的藤壶妈妈。
Ha-ha-ha!
I love this one!
哈哈哈！
我喜欢这个！
Who's a cutesy wittle tree?
谁是可爱的智慧树？
You are!
你是！
Would you like to hear
a bedtime story?
你想听吗
睡前故事？
Once upon a fertilizer,
there was a mama tree,
曾几何时，肥料，
有一棵树妈妈，
a baby tree, and a papa tree
who went out to the forest,
一棵婴儿树和一棵爸爸树
谁去了森林，
when they suddenly met
little Goldy Lumberjack.
当他们突然相遇
小戈尔迪伐木工。
Ugh, what a dumb story.
呃，多么愚蠢的故事啊。
Would you put a sock in it?
你会在里面放一只袜子吗？
I'm trying
to get some shut-eye.
我正在努力
休息一下。
You can talk?
你能说话吗？
I'm gonna name you Barky.
我会给你起名叫巴基。
Let go already.
已经放手了
You're wrinkling my leaves,
your filter feeding freak.
你弄皱了我的叶子
你的滤食狂。
- Hello, Sandy?
- Oh, howdy, SpongeBob.
- 你好，桑迪？
- 哦，你好，海绵宝宝。
How's your new tree doing?
Are you talking to it?
你的新树怎么样了？
你在跟它说话吗？
I'm trying, but to be honest,
我正在努力，但说实话，
I really haven't been able
to get a word in edgewise.
我真的没能做到
沿边插入一个词。
My tree's been doing
all the talking.
我的树一直在做
所有的谈话。
Are you feeling okay,
SpongeBob?
你感觉还好吗，
海绵宝宝？
Hang on.
Barky wants to talk to you.
不挂断。
巴基想和你谈谈。
Why did you leave me with
this giggling hunk o' holes?
你为何留下我
这个咯咯笑的大块头？
He's dimmer than a half-watt
bulb in a power outage.
他比半瓦还要暗
灯泡停电。
Well, smack my tail
and call me twitchy!
嗯，拍我的尾巴
并叫我抽搐！
I'll be right there!
我马上就到！
Bring me a glass of water!
Change my soil!
给我一杯水！
改变我的土壤！
Look out for the roots!
- Huh?
留意根源！
- 啊？
Ugh, your breath smells.
呃，你的呼吸有味道。
Why are you all face
and no body?
为何你们都是一脸
没有身体？
Hoo, doggy.
呼，小狗。
This little shrub
is a real chatterbox.
这小灌木
是一个真正的话匣子。
Get me out of this dump!
带我离开这个垃圾场！
A sensitive tree
like me needs sun.
一棵敏感的树
像我一样需要阳光。
Oh, it's too cold out here.
哦，这里太冷了。
The sun is too bright.
Somebody get me a sweater.
太阳太亮了。
谁给我一件毛衣。
I want to go back inside.
我想回到里面。
Aww, I wanted
to make saltwater trees,
哇哦，我想要
制作咸水树，
but this one's a bit too salty.
但这个有点太咸了。
I wonder how everyone else's
trees are doing.
我想知道其他人怎么样
树木正在做。
Ahh!
啊！
I shouldn't have let him drive!
我就不该让他开车！
Ahh!
啊！
Eh, at least Mrs. Puff
is having a good time.
呃，至少泡芙夫人
玩得很开心。
Excuse me,
打扰一下，
but this Krabby Patty
tastes awful.
但是这个蟹肉饼
味道很糟糕。
Well, you look awful,
嗯，你看起来很糟糕，
but you don't
hear me complaining.
但你不
听我抱怨。
Oh, I am offended!
哦，我生气了！
And offensive!
并且具有攻击性！
Oh, PU, what stinks?
哦，PU，什么臭？
Is that the customers,
or has the garbage man
是顾客，
或者有垃圾工
started making deliveries?
开始送货了吗？
Huh?
啊？
I'm outta here!
我要离开这里了！
This used to be
a respectable place.
这曾经是
一个受人尊敬的地方。
People are complaining
人们在抱怨
about me complaint department
complaining!
关于我 投诉部门
抱怨！
Agh, what is
that horrible noise?
啊，什么是
那可怕的噪音？
You should register that thing
as a lethal weapon.
你应该注册那个东西
作为致命武器。
What?
什么？
It's okay, buddy.
没关系，伙计。
Talent isn't everything.
天赋并不是一切。
- Huh.
- In your case, it's nothing.
- 嗯。
- 就你而言，这没什么。
And now back to "The Sir
Urchin Snail Fail Show!"
现在回到“先生
海胆蜗牛失败秀！”
Why you!
为什么是你！
What I do?
我做什么？
Yeesh, I'm just one day old,
是的，我才出生一天，
and even I can see
this show is for babies.
甚至我也能看到
这个节目是给婴儿看的。
You don't get it, do you?
你不明白，是吗？
Get what?
得到什么？
Hey!
嘿！
Out you go!
你出去吧！
Huh.
呵呵。
I'm free!
我自由了！
Ahh!
啊！
This joyride is over!
这次欢乐之旅结束了！
Does this mean
I don't get my license?
这是否意味着
我没有拿到驾照？
Hello, police department?
你好，警察局吗？
I got a lead
on that Shell City job.
我有领先优势
从事贝壳城的工作。
Hey, Squidward,
your barber called.
嘿，章鱼哥，
你的理发师打来电话。
He said he's sorry!
他说他对不起！
Philistine!
庸俗！
Come on, boys.
Let's have some fun.
来吧，孩子们。
让我们玩得开心吧。
Hmm.
唔。
Glug glug glug--
咕噜咕噜咕噜——
hey, buddy, wait your turn!
嘿，伙计，等你来！
Ahh!
啊！
Relax.
放松。
This will help you grow
big and strong.
这将帮助你成长
大而强。
Hey!
嘿！
Whaa!
哇！
- Huh?
- Thank you!
- 啊？
- 谢谢你！
So long, chump!
再见，笨蛋！
There she is!
她在那儿！
This Arbor Day anarchy
is all her fault!
这个植树节无政府状态
都是她的错！
Those trees
are ruining everything!
那些树
正在毁掉一切！
Ah, agh!
啊啊啊！
I gotta go.
我得走了。
Hey, they're made of wood.
I say we burn them.
嘿，它们是木头做的。
我说我们烧掉它们。
- Yeah!
- Yeah, burn 'em!
- 是的！
- 是的，烧掉它们！
Squidward, that's not
the spirit of Arbor Day.
章鱼哥，这不是
植树节精神。
Everyone, calm down!
大家冷静点！
I've got a plan.
我有一个计划。
Hm, ah!
嗯，啊！
Ooh.
哦。
Come one,
come all to Log-a-palooza!
来一个，
都来Log-a-palooza吧！
It's an Arbor Day extravaganza!
这是一场植树节盛宴！
All you can eat fertilizer!
肥料都可以吃！
If you're a tree,
you get in free.
如果你是一棵树，
你可以免费进入。
Howdy, folks!
各位好！
Are your roots too wrinkly?
你的根部太皱了吗？
Are your leaves feeling wilted?
你的叶子感觉枯萎了吗？
Hmm, my bark is feeling
a little rough.
嗯，我的吠叫感觉
有点粗糙。
Then try my wonderful
makeover machine,
那就试试我的精彩
改造机、
the Arbor Revitalizer!
乔木再生剂！
Look your best this Arbor Day!
Do I have any volunteers?
今年植树节，展现最美的自己！
我有志愿者吗？
Yeah, I'll give
your dumb machine a try.
是的，我会给
试试你的笨机器。
Run for your leaves!
跑去寻找你的叶子！
Everyone wait!
大家等着吧！
I love it!
我喜欢它！
I was destined to rot
in the woods somewhere,
我注定要腐烂
在某处树林里，
but look at me now!
但现在看看我！
I'm a chair!
我是一把椅子！
I've never felt so smooth.
我从未感觉如此顺利。
- Whoa.
- Phew.
- 哇哦。
- 唷。
He does look pretty handsome.
他看起来确实很帅。
I want to be a chair too.
我也想当椅子
I want to be a credenza!
我想成为一个书柜！
- I want to be a sawhorse!
- I want to be a table!
- 我想成为锯木架！
- 我想成为一张桌子！
- Me!
- Me next, me next!
- 我！
- 下一个是我，下一个是我！
Wow!
哇！
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
These guys are great!
这些家伙太棒了！
Good thinking, Sandy.
好主意，桑迪。
Furniturizing really calmed
these trees down.
家具真的很平静
这些树倒下了。
Ah!
啊!
both: Yeah, chairs rule!
两人：是的，椅子统治！
Well, most of them anyway.
好吧，无论如何，大多数都是这样。
I think I'll skip Arbor Day
next year.
我想我会跳过植树节
明年。